var Question1 = { 
		questionNumber: 10,
		question: '"Nebula" is the Latin word for:',
        answers: ['shiny','U.F.O.','cloud','what?'],
        correctAnswer: 'cloud',
        explanation: '<em>"mist" or "cloud."</em><br>Interstellar matter — mainly dust and gas — is collected in such a way that it\'s visible to Earth-bound observers, either as a glowing cloud or as a dark silhouette against a lighter background. These clouds are nebulae.',
};
var Question2 = { 
		questionNumber: 9,
		question: 'The first astronomer to mention a group of “nebulous” stars was:', 
        answers: ['Nostradamus in 1549','Spock in 2249','Ptolemy in 150 A.D.','Galileo in 1572'],
        correctAnswer: 'Ptolemy in 150 A.D.',
        explanation: '<em>Ptolemy in 150 A.D.</em><br>Until the 20th century, astronomers used the term nebula to describe any glowing, cloud-like object.  The telescopes of the day revealed very little detail about these objects, but astronomers could see enough to know that these nebulae came in different shapes.',
};
var Question3 = { 
		questionNumber: 8,
		question: 'In the 1920s, Edwin Powell Hubble made this pivotal discovery:',
        answers: ['many of the objects believed to be nebulae were in fact galaxies', 'Saturn\'s rings were actually giant hula-hoops', 'Orion\'s hair was on fire','Andromeda was sending flashlight signals every night at 8pm'],
        correctAnswer: 'many of the objects believed to be nebulae were in fact galaxies',
        explanation: '<em>many of the objects believed to be nebulae were in fact galaxies</em><br>Specifically, he observed that the Andromeda spiral nebula was actually a spiral galaxy. Today, astronomers know that galaxies and nebulae are unique objects with different characteristics.',
};
var Question4 = { 
		questionNumber: 7,
		question: 'Where do nebulae fall in the cosmic hierarchy?',
		answers: ['rockstars > rehab > nebulae > Los Angeles','galaxies > nebulae >  stars > planets','Jodie Foster > spinning rings > nebulae > umbrella drinks','dark matter > galaxies > star systems > nebulae'],
        correctAnswer: 'superclusters, clusters, galaxies, nebulae, star systems, stars, planets/moons',
        explanation: '<em>superclusters > clusters > galaxies > nebulae > star systems > stars > planets/moons</em><br>Astronomers make sense of the universe by organizing it into a series of "nested" levels. Nebulae occupy the middle, inside galaxies, filling the space between stars or enveloping stars like a cloak.',
};
var Question5 = { 
		questionNumber: 6,
		question: 'How big are Nebulae?',
		answers: ['about the size of China','20 light years','100 billion miles','one really super giant step'],
        correctAnswer: '20 light years',
        explanation: '<em>galaxies: 100,000 light years > nebulae: 20 light years > star systems: 1.5 light years</em><br>The dust and gas of a nebula are spread very thinly -- it contains fewer atoms per cubic inch than a puff of smoke. Yet because of its size, it can dim or block out other objects positioned behind it.',
};
var Question6 = { 
		questionNumber: 5,
		question: 'Astronomers classify nebulae into these two broad categories:',
		answers: ['light and dark','attractive and ugly','popular and unpopular','there and not-there'],
        correctAnswer: 'light and dark',
        explanation: '<em>light and dark</em><br>Bright nebulae are close enough to nearby stars that they glow. Dark nebulae are not close enough to stars to be illuminated, so they\'re visible only when something brighter -- a star cluster, for example -- provides a backdrop.',
};
var Question7 = { 
		questionNumber: 4,
		question: 'Dark nebulae are breeding grounds for:',
		answers: ['evil schemes','black holes','secrets','young stars'],
        correctAnswer: 'young stars',
        explanation: '<em>young stars</em><br>When ball of dust and gas starts to contract under its own gravity, it shrinks and its core begins collapsing. This causes the core to heat up and to rotate, creating the condensed material of protostar.',
};
var Question8 = { 
		questionNumber: 3,
		question: 'Some types of bright nebulae are associated with:',
		answers: ['magic','astrological scandal','star death','Carl Sagan'],
		correctAnswer: 'star death',
        explanation: '<em>star death</em><br>A nebula can be the remnant of a supernova, which occurs when a dying star explodes and throws off most of its material into space. These explosions form a visible nebula, some of which can be observed easily from Earth.',
};
var Question9 = { 
		questionNumber: 2,
		question: 'Why are nebulae so colorful?',
		answers: ['galactic condensation coats the dust, forming prisms', 'interstellar matter distorts the light into countless wavelengths','space is a big place and you need to stand out','to hide their sadness'],
        correctAnswer: 'interstellar matter distorts the light into countless wavelengths',
        explanation: '<em>interstellar matter distorts the light into countless wavelengths</em><br>Hubbell’s black and white cameras capture electromagnetic wavelengths — each of which correspond to a color.  Scientists add these colors during image processing to visualize what could never be seen by the human eye.',
};
var Question10 = { 
		questionNumber: 1,
		question: ' Orion, the nearest stellar factory to our home planet:',
		answers: ['sits about 1,450 light-years from Earth', 'is a peeping tom','is getting closer every second','is constantly complaining about "Earth music"'],
        correctAnswer: 'sits about 1,450 light-years from Earth',
        explanation: '<em>sits about 1,450 light-years from Earth</em><br>The discovery of planet-forming disks in the Orion Nebula has enormous implications. More than ever, astronomers believe that another star system like ours may hold a planet analogous to Earth -- one that has just the right conditions to support life as we know it.',
};	

var list = [Question1,Question2,Question3,Question4,Question5,Question6,Question7,Question8,Question9,Question10];

